Guide to the James Joyce Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Joyce collection
1884-1993
GEN MSS 112
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
24.7
(41 boxes)
The James Joyce Collection contains letters, manuscripts, musical settings and printed materials relating to the life and work of James Joyce, including correspondence and research materials used in the compilation of A Bibliography of James Joyce by Herbert Cahoon and John J. Slocum.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift and purchase from various sources, 1951-. For further information, please see Description of the Collection.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile Papers are negatives in cold storage and may only be consulted with the permission of the appropriate curator. Photographic prints are available in the main file.
Associated Materials
Printed books have been cataloged separately.
Scope and Contents
The James Joyce collection formed by Mr. John J. Slocum consists of letters to, by and about Joyce, manuscripts of his writings, clippings, photographs, printed books and pamphlets. The collection is described in A Bibliography of James Joyce by John J. Slocum and Herbert Cahoon, New Haven, Yale University Press, 1953. The Slocum Joyce collection was acquired by Yale in 1951. A part of it was given by Eileen and John J. Slocum; the remainder was given by Edwin J. Beinecke, '07, and Frederick W. Beinecke, '09S. No record was kept of which portion was given by which donor. Subsequent additions to the Joyce collection have been made by purchase, and by gift from John Hay Whitney, Mrs. Herbert Gorman, Herbert Cahoon, and other friends of the Library. The sources of these additions are noted in the register. The manuscript of "Exiles" is the gift of Mrs. Milton Erlanger.
Series I, Correspondence (1900-52), is organized into four subseries: Letters by James Joyce is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the recipient; Letters to James Joyce is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the author of the letter; Letters about James Joyce is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the author and then by the last name of the recipient; Letters About the Publication of Joyce's Works is arranged chronologically. (In the process of writing their bibliography, John Slocum and Herbert Cahoon corresponded with a number of Joyce's friends and relatives. This correspondence is listed in Series IV.) Throughout the list, "ALS" is used to cover all autograph, signed, material. No distinction is made between a postal card and a letter. "TLS" is used for all typed, signed, material. "P" indicates one side of a sheet; if the item is a postal card, "p" indicates one side of the card. Numbers from the Slocum and Cahoon Bibliography (e.g., S & C: E 17 b x) are given where applicable.
Series II, Writings (1903-55 ), is organized into the following subseries: Manuscripts, Typescripts and Proofs of works by James Joyce (Boxes 3-6) are arranged alphabetically by title. (Parts of works are entered under the title of the whole, e.g., "Anna Livia Plurabelle" is to be found under Finnegans Wake.); Musical Settings and Adaptations of works by James Joyce (Boxes 7-8) are arranged by Slocum Cahoon number.; Manuscripts, Typescripts and Proofs of Works About James Joyce (Box 8) are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the author and then alphabetically by title. (Similar material relating to the Slocum and Cahoon Bibliography may be found in Series IV.) Slocum and Cahoon numbers are noted where applicable. Dates are given only when the piece itself is dated. Publication dates are not noted.
Series III, Special Files (1884-1969) is organized into the following subseries: Clippings About James Joyce (Boxes 9-13); Clippings About Members of Joyce's Family (Box 13); Clippings About Works by James Joyce (Box 21); Clippings About Stage, Screen and Musical Adaptations of Works by James Joyce (Box 21); Clippings and Reviews of Works about James Joyce (Boxes 21-22); Lecture Programs, Menus and Recital Programs for Events in which James Joyce took part (Box 22); Programs and Prospecti for Lectures and Classes about James Joyce (Box 22); Photographs and Other Pictures of James Joyce and his family (Box 23); Clippings About Portraits of James Joyce (Box 23); Clippings About People Associated with James Joyce (Boxes 23-24); Clippings About Places Associated with James Joyce (Box 24): Legal documents, Miscellanea (Box 24).
In boxes 9-22, the Clippings are arranged alphabetically by subject and then chronologically. The Lecture programs, etc. (Box 22) are arranged alphabetically by the name of the sponsoring body. Photographs (Box 23) is arranged alphabetically by subject and then chronologically. Reference is made by page number to illustration published in Chester G. Anderson's James Joyce and his World, (New York Viking 1968). [Two original negatives accompanied this collection for prints in folders 448 and 449. These are stored separately.] Clippings About People Associated with Joyce, in Box 23, are arranged alphabetically by the name of the artist, by subject or by place. In Box 24, the Legal Miscellenea is arranged as prescriptions, diplomas and contracts, in that order.
Series IV, Slocum and Cahoon Material (1931-1966), is organized into five subseries: Correspondence (Boxes 25-29); Exhibitions in which Slocum Collection material appeared (Box 30); James Joyce Society material (Box 31); Notes and Miscellaneous Lists made for the Bibliography (Boxes 31-33); Publication details for the Bibliography (Box 34).
Correspondence contains letters to and by John Slocum, Herbert Cahoon, and R.F. Roberts in the preparation of A Bibliography of James Joyce. The letters are arranged alphabetically by the last name of the person corresponding with these three men. The last name of Slocum, Cahoon or Roberts is also given. Dates are given by year only, and the number of letters includes both letters by and letters to Slocum, Cahoon or Roberts. (e. g., "Abbott, Berenice 1947 1 Slocum" indicates that one letter passed between Berenice Abbott and Slocum in 1947.) Exhibition material (Box 30) includes correspondence about, and lists and photographs of exhibitions in which Slocum Collection material appeared. The Paris exhibition material is in Folder 1. Other exhibitions are arranged alphabetically by sponsoring body. Box 30 also contains bylaws, speeches, and correspondence (correspondence arranged as in Boxes 1-9) in that order. The Pubication Material in Box 34 contains correspondence, contracts, typescripts, and proofs, in that order.
Series V, Slocum and Cahoon Material (1967-1993) contains miscellaneous materials collected at the Beinecke Library after the collection was originally processed. It consists of three subseries each arranged alphabetically: Correspondence; Other Material; and Writings About Joyce.
Series VI, Material Removed From Cataloged Printed Items contains materials which were removed from printed items when a group of Slocum and Cahoon was cataloged in 1998.
Authors, Irish -- 20th Century -- Archives; Bibliographers; Cahoon, Herbert, 1918-2000; Joyce, James, 1882-1941 -- Musical settings; Joyce, James, 1882-1941; Slocum, John J., 1914-
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1900-1952; (5 boxes)
  - LETTERS BY JOYCE TO
    - Barnacle, Mrs. Thomas 3 ALS (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      1936 Oct 15 Paris
      1939 Jan 1 Paris
      1940 Jun 18 Périguy
    - Barnacle, Kathleen
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Griffin, Mrs. John, Box 1, folder 10
    - Bollach, Lily 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1923 Dec 18 Paris
    - Budgen, Frank 91 ALS 2 TLS
      - 1918 Sep 5 Zurich 1919 Jun 19 Zurich 1919 Jul 11 Zurich 1919 Nov 7 Trieste [1919] Trieste (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - 1919 Dec 23 Trieste 1920 Jan 3 Trieste [1920] [Trieste] [1920] Trieste 1920 Feb 24 Trieste
      - 1920 Mar 15 Trieste 1920 Mar 26 Trieste 1920 May 18 Trieste 1920 Jul 27 Paris 1920 Sep ? Paris
      - 1920 Sep 29 Paris 1920 Oct 24 Paris 1920 Nov ? Paris 1920 Dec 10 Paris 1920 Dec 20 Paris
      - 1921 May 27 Paris 1921 May 31 Paris 1921 Jun ? Paris 1921 Aug 16 Paris 1921 Sep 6 Paris
      - 1921 Nov 6 Paris 1921 Nov 23 Paris 1922 Jan 31 Paris
      - 1927 Dec 14 Paris 1927 Dec 17 Paris (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - 1928 Jan 13 Paris 1928 May 27 Paris 1928 Aug 6 Salzburg 1928 Dec 15 Neuilly 1928 Dec 31 Paris
      - 1928 ? 27 Paris 1929 Jul 22 Torquay 1929 Aug 15 Bristol 1930 Nov 27 Zurich 1932 Mar 1 Paris
      - 1932 Jun 17 Paris 1932 Aug 1 Bundesfeir 1932 Oct 9 Nice 1932 Oct 18 Nice 1932 Oct 29 Paris
      - 1933 May 24 Zurich 1933 May 29 Zurich 1933 Jul 10 Zurich 1933 Jul 17 Zurich 1933 Aug 2 Genève
      - 1933 Aug 21 Genève [with postscript] 1933 Aug 24 Genève 1933 Sep 10 Paris 1933 Dec 25 Paris 1933 Dec 30 Paris
      - 1934 Apr 1 Ventimiglia 1934 Apr 25 Paris 1934 May 2 Paris 1934 Aug 13 Spa, Belgium 1934 Sep 5 Genève
      - 1934 Sep 8 Genève 1934 Sep 22 Zurich 1934 Dec 18 Zurich 1935 Apr 5 Paris 1935 Apr 15 Paris
      - 1935 Oct 8 Paris 1935 Dec 30 Paris 1936 Jan 27 Paris 1936 Feb 29 Paris 1936 Apr 27 Paris
      - 1936 Sep 13 Paris 1936 Dec 22 Paris 1937 Feb 27 Paris 1937 Aug 9 Paris 1937 Aug 14 Basel
      - 1937 Aug 28 Zurich 1937 Sep 9 Dieppe 1937 Sep 20 Paris 1937 Oct 13 Paris 1937 Dec 22 Paris
      - 1938 Dec 25 Paris 1939 Jul ? Paris 1939 Jul 22 Étretat 1939 Aug 17 Bern 1939 Aug 20 Bern 1939 Sep 5 Paris S & C: E 17 b x 1939 Sep 18 La Baule
      - 1940 Jan 9 S. Gérand-le-Puy 1940 Feb 8 S. Gérand-le-Puy 1940 Feb 26 S. Gérand-le-Puy 1940 Mar 13 S. Gérand-le-Puy No date No place "Sunday" No date No place
    - Byrne, John Francis 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 5)
      1902 Dec 15 Paris S & C: E 1 e ii
    - Carlow, Lionel Dawson-Damer, Viscount 18 ALS
      Includes:
      (1) TLS from Paul Léon to Viscount Carlow, 1936 Aug 6
      (2) Lettrine by Lucia Joyce
      (3) Typescript copy of the Epilogue to Ibsen's "Ghosts" (S & C: E 11 c v)
      - 1936 Feb 4 Paris 1936 Jul 22 Paris 1936 Sep 1 Copenhagen 1937 Feb 18 Paris 1937 Mar 4 Paris (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - 1937 May 9 Paris 1937 Jun 6 Paris 1937 Aug 31 Zurich 1937 Sep 14 Dieppe 1937 Nov 1 Paris
      - 1937 Dec 22 Paris 1938 Jun 3 Paris 1938 Jun 17 Paris 1938 Sep 8 Lausanne 1939 Jan 28 Paris
      - 1939 Jul 15 Paris 1939 Aug 12 Lausanne 1939 Nov 4 Paris
    - Craig, Maurice James 2 ALS (Box 1, Folder 7)
      1938 Aug 24 Lausanne
      1938 Sep 23 Dieppe
    - Davray, Henry 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 8)
      1920 Jun 2 Trieste
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John 1 TL (Box 1, Folder 9)
      1904 Jun 3 Dublin typed copy
    - Griffin, Mrs. John 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 10)
      1936 Sep 30 Paris
    - Guillermet, Fanny 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 11)
      1918 Sep 5 Zurich
    - Healy, Michael 7 ALS 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 12)
      1915 Nov 2 Zurich S & C: E 11 b iv
      1920 Dec 30 Paris
      1927 Jul 1 Paris
      1933 Dec 20 Paris
      [1935 Jun 15] Paris
      1935 Jun 28 Paris
      [1935 Jul 1] Paris
      [1935 Jul 13] Paris
    - Huntington, Constant 1 TL (Box 1, Folder 13)
      1932 May 22 Paris typed copy; S & C: E 13 b
    - Joyce, May
      See: Monaghan, Mrs. Mary, Box 1, folder 17
    - Linati, Carlo 12 ALS 1 TL
      A note to Linati from James Joyce is appended to a
      letter from Ezra Pound to Linati (1920 Jun 9)
      See: Box 2, folder 59
      - 1918 Oct 31 Zurich S & C: E 16 d 1919 Dec 10 Trieste 1919 Dec 19 Trieste typed copy 1920 Mar 8 Trieste 1920 Mar 10 [Trieste] (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - 1920 May 2 Trieste 1920 May 11 Trieste 1920 Jul 1 Trieste 1920 Sep 6 Paris 1920 Sep 21 Paris 1920 Nov 3 Paris 1921 Feb 18 Paris 1921 Aug 14 Paris
    - Mann, Adolph 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 15)
      1910 Jun 24 Trieste photocopy
      [photocopy of letter privately owned]
    - Mathews, Elkin 8 ALS (Box 1, Folder 16)
      1906 Oct 17 Rome S & C: E 11 b vii
      1907 Mar 21 Trieste
      1909 Jul 12 Trieste
      1910 May 15 Trieste
      1912 May 30 Trieste
      1912 Oct 7 Trieste
      1913 Feb 26 Trieste
      1913 Easter Trieste
    - Monaghan, Mrs. Mary 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 17)
      1931 May 11 London
    - Morris, Lloyd 2 ALS (Box 1, Folder 18)
      1925 Jun 22 Paris
      1925 Jun 29 Paris
    - Murray, Mrs. John 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 19)
      1910 Jun 3 Trieste
    - Pinker, James B. 1 ALS 2 telegrams
      For other business letters, see letters about
      the publication of Joyce's works, box 2
      - 1919 May 14 Zurich 1919 Nov 22 Trieste 1920 Jul 13 Paris (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Richards, Grant 23 ALS 2 TLS
      the publication of Joyce's works, Box 2
      - 1915 Jan ? Venice S & C: E 11 b i 1915 Feb 2 Venice 1915 Mar 4 Venice 1915 Mar 24 Venice 1915 Apr 5 Venice (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - 1915 Apr 19 Venice 1915 Apr 22 Venice 1915 May 7 Venice 1915 Jul 15 Zurich 1915 Nov 22 Zurich
      - 1917 Feb 27 Zurich 1917 Mar 7 Zurich 1917 Apr 22 Zurich 1917 Jul 7 Zurich 1917 Jul 18 Zurich
      - 1917 Aug 8 Zurich 1917 Nov 30 Locarno 1918 Jan 19 Zurich 1918 Feb 11 Zurich 1918 Apr 15 Zurich
      - 1918 May 3 Zurich 1918 Jun 6 Zurich S & C: E 4 c 1918 Jul 28 Zurich 1918 Sep 8 Zurich 1918 Sep 12 Zurich
    - Roberts, George 1 ALS
      1904 Oct 5 Dublin
      See: Box 2, folder 31
    - Squire, Sir John Collings 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 22)
      1917 Apr 11 Zurich
    - Sullivan, John 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 23)
      1935 Aug 28 Paris photocopy
    - Sykes, Claud W. 32 ALS
      - 1917 Sep 16 Zurich S & C: E 11 b xix 1917 Oct 20 Locarno 1917 Nov 6 Locarno 1917 Nov 24 Locarno 1917 Nov 27 Locarno (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - 1917 Dec 12 Locarno 1917 Dec 16 Locarno 1917 Dec 17 Locarno 1917 Dec 17 Locarno S & C: E 11 b xx 1917 Dec 22 Locarno
      - 1917 Dec 27 Locarno 1918 Jan 2 Locarno 1918 Feb 4 Zurich 1920 Feb 24 Trieste 1920 May 24 Trieste
      - 1920 Jul 29 Paris 1920 Aug 29 Paris 1920 Oct 11 Paris Early 1921 Paris Spring 1921 Paris
      - 1921 Jun 6 Paris 1921 Jul 22 Paris 1927 Feb 10 Paris 1927 Feb 26 Paris 1927 Mar 22 Paris
      - 1927 Jun 10 Amsterdam 1927 Nov 23 Paris 1927 Nov 29 Paris 1928 Jan 1 Paris 1929 Jun 11 Paris
      - 1929 Aug 13 Torquay 1936 Aug 28 Elsinore
    - Wallace, Richard 1 ALS (Box 1, Folder 25)
      1924 Apr 8 Paris
    - Walsh, Ernest 2 ALS 1 TLS (Box 1, Folder 26)
      1925 Mar 13 Paris
      1925 Aug 10 Niort
      1925 Aug 15 Arcachon
    - Weaver, Harriet 38 TL
      Gift of Mrs. Herbert Gorman, 1965. Typed copies with
      Miss Weaver's autograph notes. For other business
      letters, see letters about the publication
      of Joyce's works, Box 2
      - 1923 Sep 17 Paris 1923 Oct 23 Paris 1923 Nov 19 Paris 1924 Jan 16 Paris 1924 Feb 8 Paris 1924 Mar 7 Paris (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1924 Mar 24 Paris 1924 Jun 27 Paris 1924 Nov 16 Paris 1925 Apr 11 Paris 1925 Apr 25 Paris
      - 1925 Aug 29 Arcachon 1925 Oct 22 Paris 1925 Nov 5 Paris 1926 Mar 5 Paris 1926 Apr 17 Paris
      - 1926 May 21 Paris 1926 Jun 7 Paris 1926 Jul 25 Paris 1926 Nov 15 Paris 1927 Feb 1 Paris S & C: E 17 b vi
      - 1927 Mar 2 Paris 1927 Apr 16 Paris 1927 May 12 Paris 1927 May 31 La Haye 1927 Oct 28 Paris
      - 1927 Oct 29 Paris 1927 Nov 4 Paris 1927 Nov 9 Paris 1928 Mar 28 Rouen 1928 Aug 8 Salzburg
      - 1929 Jul 16 Torquay 1930 Nov 22 Paris 1931 Feb 16 Paris S & C: E 17 b ix 1931 Mar 4 Paris 1931 Oct 27 Paris
      - 1932 Sep 6 Feldkirch 1932 Nov 25 Paris
    - [EMPTY FOLDER] (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Formerly unidentified ALS moved to folder 4,
      dated 1933 Aug 21, as postscript to existing
      letter to Frank Budgen
    - Envelopes without letters addressed to Frank Budgen, Michael Healy, and Carlo Linati. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      62 envelopes
  - LETTERS TO JOYCE FROM
    - AE
      See: Russell, George, Box 2, folder 42
    - Archer, William 3 ALS 2 TLS (Box 2, Folder 30)
      1900 Apr 23 London
      1900 Sep 15 London S & C: E 11 a v
      1901 Sep 15 London
      1901 Sep 26 London
      1902 Nov 25 London
    - Beckley, Pendleton 1 TLS
      1929 Mar 27 Paris See: Box 5, folder 129
    - Berlitz School 2 ALS 1 TLS 3 telegrams (Box 2, Folder 31)
      1904 Sep 17 Mkt Rasen From Evelyn Gilford
      1904 Sep 23 London From Berlitz
      1904 Sep 23 Mkt Rasen From Police
      1904 Oct 3 Mkt Rasen From Evelyn Gilford
      1904 Oct 4 Mkt Rasen From Evelyn Gilford
      1904 Oct 5 Dublin From Joyce to George Roberts
    - Byrne, John Francis 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 32)
      1904 Aug 19 Carrigmore
    - Dublin Printing Company 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 33)
      1904 Aug [14 or 17] Dublin
    - Ghezzi, Charles 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 34)
      No year Nov 15 London
    - Gilford, Evelyn
      See: Berlitz School, Box 2, folder 31
    - Gogarty, Oliver St. John 1 AL (Box 2, Folder 35)
      No date Vienne Fragment
    - Gonne, Maude 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 36)
      No date Paris Dated: "Friday"
    - Jung, Carl Gustav 1 TL (Box 2, Folder 37)
      1932 Aug ? Zurich
      2 photocopies, one with a note by Mary
      Colum stating that the typed copy made
      by Paul Léon is all that survives.
    - Linati, Carlo 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 38)
      1920 Mar 6 Milan - includes annotations by Joyce
      re: translations of Joyce works
    - Moult, Thomas 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 39)
      1933 Jun 9 London
    - Nast-Kalb & Schumacher 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 40)
      1906 Jun 9 Rome
    - Pinker, James B. 1 AL (Box 2, Folder 41)
      1915 Mar ? London Copy in Joyce's hand
      For other business letters, see letters about the
      publication of Joyce's works, Box 2
    - Russell, George William 4 ALS (Box 2, Folder 42)
      1902 Aug ? Dublin
      1902 Oct ? Dublin
      1902 Nov 20 Dublin
      1904 Jun ? Dublin
    - Schmitz, Ettore
      See: Svevo, Italo, Box 2, folder 44
    - Skeffington, Francis S 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 43)
      1903 Sep 29 Dublin
    - Svevo, Italo 2 ALS (Box 2, Folder 44)
      1910 Jun 15 London
      1914 Jun 26 Trieste
    - Synge, John Millington 1 ALS (Box 2, Folder 45)
      No date No place Fragment
      1903 Mar 8 Paris
    - Université de Paris 1 TLS (Box 2, Folder 46)
      1902 Nov 20 Paris
    - Yeats, William Butler 4 ALS 1 AL 1 TLS (Box 2, Folder 47)
      No date Euston Row
      1902 Oct ? No place Fragment
      1902 Nov 3? Dublin
      1902 Dec 18 London Dictated
      1904 Oct 2 Galway
  - LETTERS ABOUT JOYCE:
    - Beach, Sylvia
      3 ALS to Harry Crosby
      1928 Oct 12 Paris
      1928 Mar 19, Paris
      1928 Mar 23 Paris
      See: SERIES II, Box 6, folder 128
    - Beach, Sylvia TLS to Crosby Gaige 1928 Jun 7 Paris
      See: SERIES II, Box 5, folder 113
    - Beckett, Samuel TLS to Philippe Soupault 1930 Jul 5 Paris
      See: SERIES II, Box 5, Folder 102
    - Boyd, Ernest TLS to Crosby Gaige 1928 Feb 18
      In: Beinecke Library IIq.J853.G3 [Joyce's "Gas from a Burner"] [Letter explains references in this work]
    - Brentano's
      See: Shaylor, H, Box 2, folder 62
    - Brown, T. P. (Box 2, Folder 48)
      ALS to Mrs. John S. Joyce 1890 Mar 9
      Clongowes Wood College
    - Cape, Herbert J (Box 2, Folder 49)
      TLS to James B. Pinker 1916 Jan 26 London
      Includes a Reader's report on Portrait
      of the Artist as a Young Man.
    - Dowden, Edward (Box 2, Folder 50)
      ALS to Charles Garnier No date No place
    - Duckworth & Co.
      See: Cape, Herbert J, Box 2, folder 49
    - Gilbert, Stuart (Box 2, Folder 51)
      TLS to Mr. Roberts 1938 Mar 20 Paris
    - Housman, A. E. (Box 2, Folder 52)
      ALS to Grant Richards 1922 Jun 24 Cambridge
    - Joyce, George (Box 2, Folder 53)
      ALS to Carlo Linati 1930 May 18 Zurich
    - Joyce, Lucia (Box 2, Folder 54)
      TLS to Frank Budgen 1933 Sep 3 Paris
    - Joyce, Lucia
      Lettrine See: Box 1, Folder 6
    - Joyce, Nora (Box 2, Folder 55)
      ALS to Frank Budgen 1920 Jan 27 Trieste
    - Joyce, Nora (Box 2, Folder 56)
      ALS to James B. Pinker 1917 May 6 Zurich
    - Joyce, Stanislaus (Box 2, Folder 57)
      3 ALS to Carlo Linati
      1941 Jun 17 Florence
      1941 Jul 6 Florence
      1941 Sep 22 Florence
    - Joyce, Stanislaus (Box 2, Folder 58)
      ALS to Ellsworth Mason 1952 Mar 9 Trieste
      Accompanied by a typed copy of Open Letter to Dr.
      Oliver Gogarty and a TLS from Norman Holmes
      Pearson to Ellsworth Mason (1952 Nov 16) and
      Mason's undated reply. Gift of Ellsworth Mason, 1953.
    - Joyce, Stanislaus (Box 2, Folder 59)
      ALS to Elkin Mathews 1907 Jul 19 Trieste
    - Léon, Paul TLS to Viscount Carlow 1936 Aug 6 Paris
      See: Box 1, folder 6.
    - Linati, Carlo ALS to Ezra Pound No date Como
      See: Pound, Ezra, Box 2, folder 61
    - Mason, Ellsworth ALS to Norman Holmes Pearson No date No place
      See: Joyce, Stanislaus, Box 2, folder 58
    - Mercanton, Jacques TLS to Maurice James Craig 1938 Sep 9 Lausanne
    - Monnier, Adrienne TLS to Gaston Gallimard 1931 Jun 18 Paris
      See: SERIES II, Box 5, folder 106
    - Monnier, Adrienne AL to Germaine Pascal 1931 Jun 20 Paris - copy
      See: SERIES II, Box 5, folder 107
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes TLS to Ellsworth Mason 1952 Nov 16 New Haven
    - Pound, Ezra (Box 2, Folder 60)
      ALS to Carlo Linati 1920 Jun 9 Sirmione
      With a post script by James Joyce, and a draft
      of a reply by Carlo Linati.
    - Pound, Ezra (Box 2, Folder 61)
      TLS to James B. Pinker 1916 Jan 30 Colemans Hatch
      With Pound's autograph postscript and corrections.
    - Rousseau, Théodore TLS to Crosby Gaige 1928 Feb 1 Paris
      See: Series II, Box 5, folder 114
    - Shaylor, H. (Box 2, Folder 62)
      TLS to Ralph Pinker 1929 Jun 15 London
    - Skeffington, Mrs. Francis (Box 2, Folder 63)
      ALS to Jacob Schwartz 1932 Aug 31 Dublin
    - Terry, Simone (Box 2, Folder 64)
      TLS to Henry Gerson 1951 May 23 Paris
    - Weaver, Harriet Shaw (Box 2, Folder 65)
      ALS to Mrs. Barnacle 1939 No month No place
      calling card
    - Weaver, Harriet Shaw (Box 2, Folder 66)
      TLS to Carlo Linati 1922 Sep 8 London
    - Yeats, William Butler (Box 2, Folder 67)
      ALS to Ezra Pound 1919 Jul 15 London
    - Unidentified (Box 2, Folder 68)
      AL to Carlo Linati No date No place
  - LETTERS ABOUT THE PUBLICATION OF JOYCE'S WORKS
    - 1915-1929 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      1915 Aug 5 Weaver, Harriet Shaw. ALS to James B.
      Pinker
      1915 Aug 19 Dorrian, Cecil TLS to James B. Pinker
      1915 Sep 6 Richards, Grant TLS to James B. Pinker
      1915 Nov 5 Laurie, T. Werner TLS to James B. Pinker
      1916 Jan 17 Laurie, T. Werner TLS to James B. Pinker
      1916 Mar 22 Weaver, Harriet Shaw ALS to James B.
      1916 Jun 16 Huebsch, B. W. TL to Harriet Weaver.
      Copy.
      1917 Mar 8 Unwin, T. Fisher TLS to Harriet Shaw Weaver
      1917 Jun 22 Monroe, Harriet ALS to James B. Pinker
      1917 Aug 23 Richards, Grant TLS to James B. Pinker
      1918 Jan 18 Slack, Monro, Saw & Co. TLS to James B.
      1918 Jan 29 Slack, Monro, Saw & Co. TLS to James B.
      1918 May 16 Huebsch, B. W. TLS to James B. Pinker
      1918 Jul 15 Weaver, Harriet Shaw ALS to James B.
      1919 Feb 3 Weaver, Harriet Shaw ALS to James B. Pinker
      1919 Nov 17 Weaver, Harriet Shaw ALS to James B.
      1920 Jul 23 Huebsch, B. W. TLS to James B. Pinker
      1920 Sep 6 Castillo, J. Ruis TLS to James B. Pinker
      1921 Sep 5 Weaver, Harriet Shaw TLS to James B.
      Pinker photocopy [from unknown source]
      1922 May 31 Peacock, Walter TLS to James B. Pinker
      1922 Aug 15 Unidentified TL (signed "F") to Jepson
      photocopy [from unknown source]
      1922 Nov 10 Richards, Grant TLS to Harriet Shaw
      Weaver
      with envelope
      1923 Oct 11 Weaver, Harriet Shaw TLS to James B.
      1924 Oct 9 Cape, Herbert Jonathan TLS to Eric Pinker
      1927 May 11 Pinker, Eric TLS to Ralph Pinker
      1928 Mar 6 Tomlinson, Paul G. TL to Frederic Warde
      carbon copy; accompanied by layout instructions